A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Trip report: province of Misamis Oriental and city of Cagayan de Oro, August 20-29, 1974, August 26 (Reports 011559) (Box 502)
  The trip by Ozzie Simmons-who in 1974 was a Program Officer in the Bangkok Office-was for the purpose of gathering information to determine if the Ford Foundation would develop a technical assistance program in Misamis Oriental, Philippines.
  Technical assistance -- Philippines
- An early childhood program initiative and "Work/Family initiative" Discussion papers for the March 1988 meeting of the Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs and Urban and Rural Poverty Committees. (Reports 011560) (Box 502)
  Prepared for the March 1988 meeting of the Human Rights, Governance and International Affairs Committee and the Urban and Rural Poverty Committee of the Board of Trustees. Contains Discussion papers titled "Work/Family Initiative" and "An Early Childhood
  2 v.
  Work/family initiative; An early childhood program initiative
  Family policy; Work and family; Women -- Employment; Women -- Family relationships; Family day care; Education
- The demonstration as a strategy of change (Reports 011561), 1964 (Box 502)
  79 leaves.
  Mobilization for Youth Training Institute Workshop (1964, April 30: Columbia University)
  Action research; Social service -- Citizen participation; Social service -- Finance
- Report on SACHED's "university college" project 1984? (Reports 011562) (Box 502)
  "Based on a site visit November 15-30, 1984."-t.p.
  08400834
  22, [4] leaves.
  Education, Higher -- South Africa; Universities and colleges -- South Africa; Discrimination in education -- South Africa
- A microeconomic analysis of rural-urban migration in Haiti (Reports 011563), 1979 (Box 503)
  07650356
  184 leaves.
  Rural-urban migration -- Haiti -- Econometric models
- Attachments, 1977-1982. (Reports 011565)
  Contains: Proceedings of IDP Popteam Coordinators' Conference, March 22-23, 1979; Institutional Development Program Interim Report, 1977-1979; A General Report on the IDP Consultative Review Project Covering a Period of Five Months (August-December, 1979),
  7700354
  Population research -- Philippines
- Proceedings of IDP Institutional Development Program PopTeam coordinators' conference, March 22-23 (Reports 011565-001), 1979 (Box 503)
  07700354
- Institutional Development Program interim report, 1977 (Reports 011565-002), 1979 (Box 503)
- A general report on the IDP Institutional Development Program consultative review project covering a period of five months (August -December, 1979) (Reports 011565-003) (Box 503)
- Report on assessment workshop, Institutional Development Program Phase III, October 18-19, 1982, PCF Building (Reports 011565-004) (Box 503)
- Institutional Development Program terminal report phase III (Reports 011565-005), 1982 (Box 503)
- Agenda items from the meeting of the Trustee Personnel and Administration Committee, June 22 (Reports 011566), 1977 (Box 503)
  var. pag.: attachments -- 28 cm.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Personnel management; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Salaries, etc.; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Archives; Ford Foundation
- A memorandum on teaching and research in Southeast Asian studies in Indonesia, November 11 (Reports 011567), 1969 (Box 503)
  Teaching and research in Southeast Asian studies in Indonesia
  Education, Higher -- Research -- Indonesia
- Image of women in advertisements: A preliminary study of avenues for change (Reports 011568), 1975 (Box 503)
  07450617
  Women in advertising; Sexism in mass media
- A review of social science research at INCAP Institute of Nutrition of Central America and Panama with special reference to the work of the rural development unit (Reports 011569), 1977 (Box 503)
  Site visit team report. --T.p.
  Project to facilitate interaction among scholars concerned with research on Latin American education.
  24 p. -- 28 cm.
  Social sciences -- Research -- Central America; Rural development -- Central America; Endowments -- Central America -- Evaluation
- Report on the seminar on recent developments in international economic relations: held on January 5, 1977 at New Delhi under the auspices of the Ford Foundation (Reports 011570) (Box 503)
  This seminar was sponsored by the Ford Foundation's New Delhi office and "was attended by a large number of individuals consisting of Indian government officials, government and university economists, public and private sector senior management staff..."
  40 leaves.
  Report
  Seminar on Recent Developments in International Economic Relations (1977: New Delhi, India) Report
- The international legal studies program of the Ford Foundation: report and recommendations, 1969 Dec. (Reports 011571) (Box 503)
  Includes: 4 page memorandum to Howard Swearer from E.G. Barber with a critique of the report by Schwartz.
  38, 4 leaves.
  International law -- Study and teaching
- Consulting reports on population, November 15 (Reports 011572), 1976 (Box 503)
  Contains consultant reports by Thomas W. Merrick and Harley L. Browning written as memoranda to Robert S. Drysdale and John Nagel; a summary of the reports in a memorandum from Nagel to Drysdale; memorandum about the reports from Barry R. Schumann to Drysda
  18, 14, 6, 1 leaves.
  Report on consulting visit in Mexico, October 26-30, 1976; Report on consulting visit in Mexico, October 24-31, 1976; Consulting reports of Harley Browning and Thomas Merrick: visit of October 24-31, 1976
  Population research -- Mexico
- Displacement: where we are (Reports 011573), 1980 (Box 504)
  Discusses different views of the displacement of low-income urban residents by gentrification and revitalization.
  Relocation (Housing) -- United States; Gentrification; Urban policy -- United States; Urban renewal -- United States
- Mexican politics: balance and prospects (Reports 011574), 1977 (Box 504)
  59 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Political science -- Mexico; Political participation -- Mexico; Economic development -- Mexico
- Background paper for the workshop on Western water issues and rural America (Reports 011575), 1980 (Box 504)
  08090555
  Western Water Issues and Rural America (1980: Ford Foundation)
  Water-supply, Rural
- Foundations and higher education at home and abroad: A tale of heroic efforts abandoned (Reports 011576), 1986 (Box 504)
  Education, Higher -- Aims and objectives; Education, Higher -- Endowments; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Evaluation
- Evaluating the effects of Ford Foundation support for education abroad of Third World nations, 1960-1980: a pre-proposal (Reports 011577), 1982 (Box 504)
  Includes one-page memorandum to William Carmichael.
  1, 44 leaves.
  Educational evaluation -- Developing countries; Foreign study -- Developing countries
- New challenges for rural economic development: a final report to the Ford Foundation, June 15 (Reports 011578), 1982 (Box 504)
  Contains 11 chapters as follows: Summary and Overview; The Changing Nature of Rural America; A Summary of Employment Trends Affecting Non-Metropolitan Areas in the United States; The Status of Women and Minorities in Non-Metropolitan America; Case Study:
  08100310; 820-0955.
  [2], 29, 29, 28, 29, 14, 18, 15, 23, 43, 20, 23 pages.
  Labor supply -- United States -- Regional disparities; Rural women -- United States; Rural development -- United States; Manpower policy, Rural -- United States; Regional planning; Rural population -- United States
- Rural America: a new public policy frontier (Reports 011579), 1983 (Box 504)
  This paper was prepared for the Congressional Symposium, "Agricultural Communities: The Relationship of Agriculture, Business, Industry and Government in the Rural Economy," held May 19-20, 1983 in Washington, D.C.
  United States and International Affairs Program/Rural Poverty and Resources; United States and International Affairs Program/Rural Poverty and Resources
  08200955
  The Regents of the University of California
  42 leaves.
  Rural development -- United States -- Government policy; Rural population -- United States
- National Rural Fellows: a tool for capacity building in rural areas 1980? (Reports 011580) (Box 504)
  08150658
  26, [17] leaves.
  Rural development -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Minorities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.
- A technical assistance project for the development of small industries in East Pakistan: summary project report (Reports 011581), 1971 (Box 504)
  Discusses small industry in East Pakistan and evaluates the East Pakistan Small Industries Corporation (EPSIC) and its Small Industry Advisory Service (SIAS).
  06400454
  101, 2 pages.
  Technical assistance -- Bangladesh; Economic development projects -- Bangladesh; Small business -- Bangladesh -- Finance
- Computer needs of the State of Bahrain (Reports 011582), 1973 (Box 504)
  Computers -- Bahrain; Economic development projects -- Bahrain
- Public television: financial information: report to the Ford Foundation (Reports 011583), 1969 (Box 504)
  Reviews financial situation of public television stations for 1965-1968, and contains projections for 1968-1972.
  Public television -- United States -- Finance
- An overview of PIACT related product studies in Mexico January 1978? (Reports 011584) (Box 504)
  Includes: 2 page memorandum to Peter S. Cleves summarizing PIACT activities between October and December 1977.
  2, 13 leaves.
  Contraceptives -- Research -- Mexico
- The Ford Foundation in Bangladesh, September 1978. (Reports 011585) (Box 504)
  Covers period 1971-1978.
  Technical assistance -- Bangladesh
- Rural development and agriculture in Cuba (Reports 011586), 1979 (Box 504)
  Rural Sociological Society Meetings (1979: Burlington, Vt.)
  Agriculture -- Cuba; Rural development -- Cuba
- The Ford Foundation's population program in Bangladesh (FY75) (Reports 011587), 1975 (Box 504)
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific; International Division/Population Program
  17, [7] leaves.
  Population assistance -- Bangladesh
- The Ford Foundation's program in development planning and management, November 17 (Reports 011588), 1975 (Box 504)
  7,[2] leaves.
  Public administration -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Business education -- Bangladesh
- Graduate history programs in Brazil 1975? (Reports 011589) (Box 504)
  History -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Brazil
- Informal reports on Pakistan program, 1964 (Reports 011590) (Box 504)
  Informal reports on Foundation activities in Pakistan for January-March 1964 and December 1964-December 1965. Reports outline grant actions, new project explorations, significant developments under grants, visitors and staff travel, reports received, and
  5 v.: var. pag. -- 28 cm.
- Overseas Development Program, Pakistan: plans and estimates January, 1956 to October, 1959, January 31, 1956. (Reports 011591) (Box 505)
  34 leaves.
  Technical assistance -- Pakistan
- Pakistan reports, program reviews, and newsletters, 1953 (Reports 011592) (Box 505)
  Reports discuss conditions in Pakistan and Foundation programs there, including the establishment of the field office. Includes tour reports by Aftab Akhtar and A. K. Malik, the executive secretary and leader of a Foundation sponsored tour by 27 Pakistani
  Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Community development -- Japan; Community development -- India
- Overseas Development Program in Pakistan: status reports, 1956-1958. (Reports 011593) (Box 505)
  Contains 4 reports, each of which has descriptions of grantee activities arranged by program. Includes cover letters from George F. Gant, Representative in Karachi from 1955-1958, to Forrest F. Hill, Vice -President for the Foundation's Overseas Developme
  22, 20, 14, 13 leaves.
- Cooperative Project for Research on Agricultural Technology in Latin America (PROTAAL): a final evaluation 198 (Reports 011594), 1980 (Box 505)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Latin America
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: program reports and budgets, April 1960-March 1961. (Reports 011595-001) (Box 505)
  Summaries of conditions in Pakistan, and detailed review of Foundation programs there. Contains three reports: Program Review and Projection, April 1960; Status of Program, October 1960; and Program Review and Program Budget, 1961-1962, March 1961.
  88, 30, 51 leaves.
  Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Educational assistance -- Pakistan
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: Status of program (Reports 011595-002), 1960 (Box 505)
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: Program review and program budget, 1961 (Reports 011595-003) (Box 505)
- Annual reports and supplements: Pakistan, 1964-1977. (Reports 011596)
  Program reports, supplements, and budget projections, fiscal years 1965-1968; semi-annual report for October 1967-November 1968; "Pakistan FY 1970: a Short Review"; program paper of June 1971 discussing the civil war and its implications for the Foundation; p
  14 volumes (5 linear inches).
  Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Educational assistance -- Pakistan; Agricultural development projects -- Pakistan; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Pakistan; Economic development -- Research -- Pakistan; Population assistance -- Pakistan
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: Program report, 1963-64 and program budget, 1964-65 (Reports 011596-001) (Box 505)
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: Program report, 1964-65 and program budget, 1965-66 (Reports 011596-002) (Box 505)
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: Program report 1965-66 (Reports 011596-003), 1966 (Box 505)
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: Program report (Reports 011596-004), 1967 (Box 505)
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: Program report (Reports 011596-005), 1968 (Box 505)
- The Ford Foundation in Pakistan: Semiannual report, October 1, 1967 to April 30 (Reports 011596-006), 1968 (Box 505)
- Pakistan program FY 1970: A short review (Reports 011596-007) (Box 505)
- Pakistan program paper (Reports 011596-008), 1971 (Box 505)
- Pakistan program report, FY (Reports 011596-009), 1972 (Box 505)
- Pakistan: Annual program status report, FY (Reports 011596-010), 1972 (Box 506)
- Pakistan: Annual program status report, FY 1973 (October 1, 1972-September 30, 1973) (Reports 011596-011) (Box 506)
- Pakistan: Annual program status report, FY (Reports 011596-012), 1974 (Box 506)
- Pakistan: Annual program status report, FY (Reports 011596-013), 1975 (Box 506)
- Pakistan: Annual program status report, FY 1975 (October 1, 1975-September 30, 1976) (Reports 011596-014) (Box 506)
- Research on race and ethnicity sponsored by the Education and Research Division and its forbears, 1951-73: A report to the Ford Foundation Task Force on Race and Ethnicity, July 2 (Reports 011597), 1973 (Box 506)
  Includes: cover memorandum by Basil Whiting; appendices listing dissertation fellowships in ethnic studies awarded FY 1971 and FY 1972, and travel and study awards in the field of race and ethnicity, 1967-1973.
  [1], 28, 8, 10, [4] leaves.
  Ethnology -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Minorities -- Study and teaching -- United States
- Management and entrepreneurship development in the provinces, October 14 (Reports 011598), 1974 (Box 506)
  Discusses potential Foundation programs in provincial and rural development in the Philippines.
  Rural development projects -- Philippines; Rural development personnel -- Training of -- Philippines
- Research on corporate giving: a critical review (Reports 011599), 1985 (Box 506)
  Corporations -- Charitable contributions
- Balance the basics: Let them write, April 7 (Reports 011600), 1977 (Box 506)
  One in a series of papers presented at an internal Foundation seminar on research on learning in the mid-1970's. This paper argues for the importance of writing along with reading and mathematics in the basic educational curriculum, examines reasons why w
  Education and Research; EPP
  07290256
  [Ford Foundation Publications]
  Written communication -- Study and teaching
- The first year of the transition toward socialism in Chile (Reports 011601), 1971 (Box 506)
  Socialism -- Chile; Political campaigns -- Chile; Political science -- Chile
- Small scale mechanization alternatives for Egypt: an economic evaluation, June 5 (Reports 011602), 1979 (Box 506)
  43 leaves.
  Farm mechanization -- Economic aspects -- Egypt
- An economic re-evaluation of the multi-crop thresher system for Egypt, October 1980/ James B. Fitch and Shawky Imam. (Reports 011603) (Box 506)
  Farm mechanization -- Economic aspects -- Egypt; Threshing machines -- Economic aspects -- Egypt
- Trip to Asia: September 1974, November 11 (Reports 011604) (Box 506)
  Memorandum to John Bresnan, dated November 11, 1974.
  7 leaves-- 28 cm.
  Social sciences -- Research -- Southeast Asia
- Notes on the world food situation: August 1974, August 16 (Reports 011605) (Box 506)
  Food supply -- International coOperation; Food crops
- The World Food Conference: impressions and reality, November 25 (Reports 011606), 1974 (Box 506)
  World Food Conference (1974: Rome, Italy)
  Food supply -- International coOperation; Agricultural productivity -- International cooperation
- Program development in linguistics and language teaching in Brazil, January 8 (Reports 011607), 1971 (Box 506)
  Includes a 1 page memorandum to William D. Carmichael.
  1, 136 leaves.
  Linguistics -- Brazil; Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Brazil
- Final report assessing community development corporations, September 30 (Reports 011608), 1975 (Box 506, Box 507)
  "An evaluation of the Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation, The Woodlawn Organization, and the Zion Non-Profit Charitable Trust."-t.p. Volume II contains 6 appendices. A - D are working papers as follows: Program Evaluation and Policy Analysis of Co
  07200088
  2 volumes (570 pages).
  Community development corporations -- Evaluation
- Conference and working papers, 1982 (Reports 011609)
  Contains papers prepared for presentation at the Conference on Viable Economic and Social Alternatives in Central America and the Caribbean, held at Stanford University, Palo Alto, California on 6-7 October 1983 and sponsored by the Stanford Center for La
  8351022
  9 volumes (2.5 linear inches).
  Economic factors in the socio-politic evolution of Central America.; Political and economic constraints of export economies in Central America and the Caribbean; Caribbean economies in transition: problems and prospects of structural adjustment; Role of the
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Caribbean Area; Labor supply -- Research; Stanford University; Caribbean Area -- Commercial policy; Caribbean Area -- Economic conditions; Caribbean Area -- History; Caribbean Area
- Economic factors in the socio-political evolution of Central America (Reports 011609-001), 1983 (Box 507)
  08351022
  Conference on Viable Economic and Social Alternatives in Central America and the Caribbean (1983: Stanford University)
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Caribbean Area; Labor supply -- Research
- Political and economic constraints of export economies in Central America and the Caribbean (Reports 011609-002), 1983 (Box 507)
- Caribbean economies in transition: Problems and prospects of structural adjustment (Reports 011609-003), 1983 (Box 507)
- The role of the major and regional powers in the search for viable alternatives in the Caribbean basin (Reports 011609-004), 1983 (Box 507)
- The role of agriculture in the search for viable economic and social alternatives: The Caribbean basin (Reports 011609-005), 1983 (Box 507)
- Historical conjuncture between European and slave cultures: Manifestations for viable alternatives in the Caribbean (Reports 011609-006), 1983 (Box 507)
- Introduction to the Conference on Central America and the Caribbean (Reports 011609-007), 1983 (Box 507)
- Project on United States-Mexico Relations, working paper, no.2: The U.S. Mexican labor market of the future (Reports 011609-008), 1982 (Box 507)
  1982 Woodlands Conference (Woodlands, Texas, November 7-10, 1982)
- Project on United States-Mexico Relations, working paper, no.4: Project description (Reports 011609-009), 1982 (Box 507)
- Project on United States-Mexico Relations, working paper, no.6: United States-Mexico trade and financial interdependence: Report on the workshop held at Stanford University on May 13-14 (Reports 011609-010), 1983 (Box 507)
- No talking, have fun and other mixed messages: naturalistic research in Girls Clubs of America's Operation SMART (Reports 011610), 1989 (Box 507)
  08500908
  Girls -- United States; Women -- Education, Secondary -- United States; Minorities -- Education (Secondary) -- United States; Women in mathematics -- Training of -- United States; Women in science -- Training of -- United States; Science -- Study and teaching
- Reports on the Foundation's activities in Southern Africa, 1972 (Reports 011611)
  The reports in this collection deal with the Ford Foundation's attempt at establishing an expanded program in southern and South Africa. The collection contains seven reports in the form of memoranda to McGeorge Bundy, David Bell and others, by the follow
  L77-170
  7 volumes (ca. 135 leaves).
  Racism -- South Africa; Refugees -- Africa, Southern; Ford Foundation -- South Africa; Ford Foundation -- Africa, Southern; South Africa -- Race relations; South Africa -- Economic conditions -- 1961-1991; South Africa -- Social conditions -- 1961
- Status and outlook for our work in southern Africa (Reports 011611-001), 1972 (Box 507)
  Racism -- South Africa; Refugees -- Africa, Southern
- Southern Africa: Program directions (Reports 011611-002), 1977 (Box 507)
- The Ford Foundation and South Africa (Reports 011611-003), 1972 (Box 507)
- South and Southern Africa refugee situation- available and potential sources of assistance (Reports 011611-004), 1977 (Box 507)
- The Republic of South Africa (Reports 011611-005), 1976 (Box 507)
- Program priorities in agriculture and rural development in the Andean region, 1977 Sept. (Reports 011612) (Box 507)
  Rural development -- Andes Region; Agricultural development projects -- Andes Region
- Assistance in the behavioral sciences: some observations and generalizations from Turkey (Reports 011613), 1972 (Box 507)
  Paper from Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa.[]Conference background paper prepared for the June 1972 Ford Foundation Conference on the Middle East and North Africa. Discusses issues that arise when doing instruction and research in the behavioral sciences in countries coping with extensive developmen
  Social sciences -- Study and teaching -- Turkey; Social science -- Research -- Turkey
- Agricultural economics in Zaire: prospective developments (Reports 011614), 1972 (Box 507)
  07590808
  39 leaves.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Zaire
- National Affairs current programs: background comments and a review (Reports 011615), 1979 (Box 507)
  Prepared in response to questions from the Board of Trustees about the focus and direction of the Foundation's programs in National Affairs. -p.1.
  Civil rights -- United States; Public interest law -- United States; Social participation -- United States; Community life -- United States
- Review of eight community development corporations which have received financial support from the Ford Foundation (Reports 011616), 1981 (Box 508)
  Reviews the Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration Corporation, Southeast Development Incorporated, South East Alabama Self-Help Association, Mississippi Action for Community Education, Southern Cooperative Development Fund/Southern Development Foundation, Mexica
  Mca828-980.
  v, 35, 331 leaves.
- The evolution of the National Tenant Management Demonstration Program (Reports 011617), 1977 (Box 508)